#### Personal Information

Address: 1599A 39th Street Los Alamos, NM 87544

Phone: +1 (920) 858-8783 Email: casey.alan.anderson@gmail.com

# CASEY A. ANDERSON

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caseyalananderson

Work Information

Address: P.O. Box 1663

Los Alamos, NM 87545

Phone: +1 (505) 667-5968 Email: casey\_a@lanl.gov

## **Executive Summary**

**Nuclear engineer** and **physicist** with six years of experience involving scientific computing, critical thinking, and analytical problem solving. Proven as a leader in student organizations, active as a team member in diverse work environments, and effective at publishing and communicating results. Highly motivated individual seeking a rewarding career on nuclear weapons and national security applications.

# **Professional Experience**

# Los Alamos National Laboratory

2010, 2011-2012, 2016-Present

GRA/PM NEN-5, Systems Design & Analysis 2016-Present
GRA/PM W-13, Advanced Engineering Analysis 2011-2012
Intern XCP-3, Monte Carlo Codes 2010

- Developing benchmarks and publishing reports on newly implemented features in MCNP [Pubs: 1,3,4,5]
- Modeling detector system responses using MCNP, Django, HTML, Javascript, and Python
- · Working with SQL databases, managing servers, and utilizing version control using Mercurial
- Assisted in the development and testing of multi-physics analysis by coupling radiation transport results in MCNP with finite-element analysis in Abaqus/CAE
- Developed unstructured mesh human phantoms for health physics applications with MCNP6 [Pub: 9]
- Developed a software visualization package for finite element geometries in MCNP simulations

# Medical College of Wisconsin

2012-2016

## Graduate Research Assistant Department of Biophysics 2012-2016

- Patented a segmented reconstruction technique for artifact reduction in MRI [Pat: i.]
- Collaborated with medical doctors and other clinical researchers to secure NIH grant funding
- Submitted abstracts and presented findings at various international conferences [Pubs: 6,7,8]

# Areas of Expertise

#### Physics/Engineering Software **Programming** Nuclear Engineering Languages MCNP Other Fourier Analysis Abaqus/CAE Python Key Technical Writing Monte Carlo Methods Linux Bash (Skill Level) Presentations • LATEX High Signal Processing Matplotlib Leadership Med/High Magnetic Resonance Imaging Matlab Matlab Version Control Regularization Methods Mercurial Med MacOS • File I/O Radiation Detectors Git Med/Low Windows Scripting Multi-physics coupling Microsoft Office C/C++ Low Debugging • Computer Aided Engineering VisIt Fortran Finite Element Analysis RELAP Java

#### **Education**

MAY 2016 M. Sc, Biophysics, Medical College of Wisconsin, GPA: 3.80/4.0

"Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping: Exploratory Development and Initiation of Processing Pipelines"

MAY 2011 M. Sc, Nuclear Engineering & Engineering Physics, University of Wisconsin - Madison, GPA: 3.44/4.0 B. Sc, Nuclear Engineering, University of Wisconsin - Madison, GPA:3.24/4.0

# **Publications & Presentations**

- 1. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Neutron and Gamma Correlations using CGM in MCNP 6.2.0 (LA-UR-20353)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting*. (San Fransisco, California). 2017, Link
- 2. § James Tutt and Gregg McKinney. "Speed and Memory Improvements to MCNP6 Delayed-Gamma Line Treatment (LA-UR-21050)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting*. (San Fransisco, California). 2017
- 3. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Delta-ray production in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-25402)". In: 24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 4. <sup>‡</sup> James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Background-Source Cosmic-Photon Elevation Scaling and Cosmic-Neutron/Photon Date Scaling in MCNP6 (LA-UR-16-24928)". In: 24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 5. James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Delayed-Gamma Energy Biasing with Exact Energy Sampling in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-24057)". In: *Proceedings of the 26th American Nuclear Society Winter Meeting*. (Las Vegas, Nevada). Oct. 2016, Link
- 6. Casey Anderson et al. "Volume-Paracellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 24th Conference.* (Singapore, Singapore). May 2016, Link
- 7. † Casey Anderson and Kevin Koch. "Volume-parcellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping of the Human Brain at 7T". in: 2015 Minnesota Workshop on High and Ultra-High Field Imaging. (Minneapolis, Minnesota). Oct. 2015, Link
- 8. Casey Anderson, Kimberley Pechman, and Kathleen Schmainda. "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping to Assess Iron Levels in Rat Brain Tumors". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 22nd Conference.* (Milan, Italy). May 2014, Link
- 9. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson, Tim Goorley, and Karen Kelley. "Mesh Human Phantoms with MCNP (LA-UR-12-01307)". In: *2012 3DS Simulia Community Conferece Proceedings*. (Providence, Rhode Island). May 2012, pp. 556–568, Link

‡Presentation Included; §Presentation Only; || Magna Cum Laude

#### **Patents**

i. Kevin Koch and Casey Anderson. System and method for localized processing of quantitative susceptibility maps in magnetic resonance imaging. WO Patent App. PCT/US2016/038,723. Dec. 2016. URL: https://www.google.com/ patents/W02016209930A1?cl=en, Link

#### Classes & Trainings

- I. "MCNP6 Intermediate Workshop", (Los Alamos New Mexico). May, 2016
- II. "CPR Certification Training", (Milwaukee, Wisconsin). May, 2015
- III. "General Electric MR Programming Workshop", (Madison, Wisconsin). Oct, 2014
- IV. "Dale Carnegie Training", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). August, 2011
- V. "Introduction to Abaqus", (Minneapolis, Minnesota). June, 2011
- VI. "Introduction to Python Programming", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). July, 2010
- VII. "MCNP5 Beginner Workshop", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). May, 2010